James Cheng

MOBILE ENGINEER

Details

Melbourne, Australia

tojamescheng@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Australian

Skills

Android Development

iOS Development

GraphQL

Git

Ruby on Rails

Node.js

Links

linkedIn

Profile

Hi, I am a mobile engineer with 4.5 years of extended experience in building apps with engaging UI, shipping apps that serve millions of users internationally, perform A/B testing and monitoring results, etc. I specialize in Android development but also growing my iOS expertise. I am looking to join a team to which I could contribute my expertise, make a positive impact, and become a valuable asset to the team.

Education

Masters of Computer Science, RMIT, Melbourne

MARCH 2015 - JULY 2016

Employment History

Mobile Engineer, Equiem, Melbourne

FEBRUARY 2020 - PRESENT

Delivering and maintaining features on Equiem apps on both Android and iOS platforms, major achievements include:

- Integrated HID access control API into Equiem iOS app.
- Automate Room database unit testing on the Android platform.
- Refactoring existing search feature to make it reusable and apply new styling.
- Monitoring crash report and maintain a crash-free rate of 98%

Android Engineer, iflix, Melbourne

JANUARY 2018 - JANUARY 2020

As an Android engineer in the Engagement space at iflix, my achievements include:

- Build and maintain the iflix Android app to achieve 50 million installs across the world.
- Contribute to the Android codebase by following best practices from Google and promoting them to the rest of the team.
- Work closely with product owners and designers to implement and release new features timely in an Agile manner.
- Monitoring app performance and general health and provide timely fixes if needed to help increase our crash-free user percentage to 99.76%.

Lead Android Developer, Kinnov, Melbourne

JUNE 2016 - DECEMBER 2017

As lead Android developer at Kinnov, my responsibility was to building point of sales apps on the ANZ BladePay $^{\text{TM}}$ platform and help my company to land a partnership with ANZ bank.

- Consult with stakeholders from ANZ bank to collect requirements and feedbacks on a weekly basis and convert them into actionable tasks.
- Produced 4 fully functional Android apps from scratch and published on the ANZ BladePay™ platform.
- Competed with other candidates and helped my company became a major partner with ANZ bank by being the first candidate to deliver fully functional POS applications that published on ANZ BladePay™ platform.